The sound of a train running alongside a river
The color of sunflowers blooming facing down
The sunset becomes a striped border
Why do I want to cry every time you say "thank you"?
I'm like a child
I thought I'd left all my tears in the fridge
Red rover, red rover, send that girl right over
Goodbye, bystander
We keep walking
Even if at the end of this road isn't Heaven or anything like that
I just want to keep being with you and smiling together
Pride, wishes, and hope
I'll always have them just like you do
When you're scared, so scared, and becoming depressed
I'll protect you, I'll always protect you with everything I have
I promise you to your face
Silver Thread
20th Lion King Tournament
Souya Touji, Lion King
vs. Shimada Kai, 8-dan
（桐山(きりやま) 零(れい)）わあっ
Th-This is the right place, isn't it?
こ ここでいいんだよな
Hesitant 17-year-old
It's a huge hotel.
でっかいホテル…
Hey!
（二海堂(にかいどう)晴信(はるのぶ)）おーい！ 桐山
Kiriyama!
Nikaidou.
（零）二海堂…
Big Brother’s being interviewed
by reporters in the waiting room.
（二海堂）兄者(あにじゃ)は今
控え室で取材中だ
This is the 20th anniversary,
so there's also a fan gathering tonight, on the eve.
今回は 20回記念で—
前夜祭の前に
ファンの集いもあるからな
It must be hard on Big Brother and the others, with the matches starting tomorrow.
あしたから対局なのに
兄者たちは大変だ
The fan gathering starts at 3:00 p.m.
ファンの集いは３時からだ
Once it starts, sit as close as you can to Big Brother in the hall.
始まったら なるべく会場で
兄者のそばにいてくれ
Hey, are you sure about this?
なあ ほんとにいいの？
We have nothing to do with this, so to sit by him is a bit...
俺たち関係ないのに そばにいてさ
Nothing to do with it?!
（二海堂）関係ない？
We're in the same workshop!
同じ研究会だろ
しかも俺は弟弟子(でし)だぞ！ おい！
Plus I'm his "little brother" disciple!
When he's surrounded by all of these
unfamiliar people and steeling himself,
大勢の慣れない人に
周りを囲まれて 気を張って—
I want to support him so he's not worn out before the first match.
対局前日に疲れちゃわないように
そばにいたいんだ
It's a relief to see a familiar face, right?
知った顔が近くにいれば
ホッとするだろ？
Also, Big Brother is usually very considerate toward others.
兄者は人一倍
気を遣ってしまう人だから
（二海堂）あ 何だ？
What is it?
Oh, it's nothing.
（零）ああ いや 何でもない
Hadn't thought it
through that far
分かった
I get it.
Nikaidou, are you actually more mature than me?
（零）二海堂 ひょっとしてお前…
俺より大人なのか？
Besides,
（二海堂）それに…
it's good to experience this atmosphere and get used to it.
この雰囲気を少しでも味わって
慣れておいたほうがいいぞ
That way, when the time comes,
I won't get too excited and lose my focus.
いざ そのときに 舞い上がって—
集中力を
欠いたりしないで済むように
（零）ん？ “いざ”って？
When what time comes?
When it's my turn to play in the title match, of course.
自分がタイトル戦に
出るときのことに決まってるだろう
Blunt
What?!
えーっ！
サクッと言ったな 今
You said that quite matter-of-factly!
Like it's a matter of course!
さも 当然みたいな感じで
Right now, we're still C1 and C2!
今 俺たち
まだＣ１とＣ２だぞ！
I'll be in it.
（二海堂）出るさ！
Lion King Tournament Opening Match Eve Presentation
I'll have my shot at the title.
絶対に タイトルに挑戦する
そう決めている
I made up my mind.
If I didn't think that, how could I go on?
そう思わないで
どうしてやっていける？
Nikaidou.
二海堂…
I saw Nikaidou's face as he said that
（零）
そう言った二海堂の顔を見て—
少なからず 僕は動揺した
and was shaken considerably.
Hey, Rei.
（幸田(こうだ)柾近(まさちか)）おい 零！
Well, see you back at the hall around three.
じゃあ ３時になったら
また会場でな
R-Right.
While I was running in circles getting lost,
（零）僕が グルグル
迷っている間に—
my peer has already hardened his resolve.
同年代の彼は
既に覚悟を固めていたのだ
I thought I should tell you if I ran into you.
（柾近）お前に会ったら
言わないといかんと思っていた
It's about your tournament prize money and match earnings.
お前 トーナメントの
賞金や対局料—
Aside from living expenses,
you've been depositing it in my bank account.
生活費以外は ほとんど
うちに振り込んでるだろう
Knowing you, maybe you think of it as payment for taking care of you all these years,
“今まで世話になった分”と—
お前のことだから
思ってるんだろうが—
but there's no need to think like that.
そんなことは
考えなくていいんだぞ
But I can't just...
でも そういうわけには…
Ba
m!
It's fine, Kouda!
（神宮寺(じんぐうじ)崇徳(たかのり)）いいじゃん 幸田
そのまま お前が預かっておけば
You hang on to the kid's money.
If a kid had a small fortune at his disposal, he'd just blow it on unsavory things.
どうせ ガキに
大金 持たせといたら—
ロクなことに使わないんだし
Chairman, Rei isn't that kind of boy.
（柾近）会長 零は
そんな子じゃありません
I see.
（神宮寺）そっか
それに そういえば—
So more than not being the type,
a boy his age can't blow money on those things.
これだけガキだと
タイプうんぬんより—
Alcohol
Cigarettes
Sketchy
bars
Gambling
カネの使い道が まだねえのか
N
o
p
N
o
p
Nope!
いや〜 かわいそうに
Poor kid.
He's got all this money, but nothing to spend it on.
せっかくの小金持ちなのに
使い道がねえとは
How about a woman?
あとは 女か？
You could support a selfish girlfriend at least?
わがままな彼女に入れ込んで
貢ぐぐらいか？
How about that angle?
どうなの？ そっち方面は
えぇ？
Kiriyama-wama! You little guy!
桐山きゅーん きゅーん
（神宮寺）この このっ…
（零）ああ 痛い…
That hurts!
Chairman, please go away.
（柾近）会長
もう あっち行ってください
Well, like the chairman said,
I'll hold on to your money until you come of age,
まあ 会長の言うとおり—
お前が成人するまでは
私が預かっておくが—
but if you ever need it, just tell me.
必要になったら
いつでも言いなさい
Oh, that's right.
そうだ…
香子(きょうこ)は… どうしてる？
How is Kyouko doing?
お前の所へ
よく行っているようだが—
Apparently she often stays over with you, but is she giving you any trouble?
迷惑かけてないか？
What is he talking about?
（零）えっ？ どういう…
So she hasn't been going to your place.
行ってないのか…
やっぱりな
I thought so.
俺には もう—
I have no idea what she's thinking anymore.
あいつの考えてることが
さっぱり分からんのだ
（零）お父さん　姉さんは…
Dad.
Sis is...
Kouda, 8-dan! Kiriyama, 5-dan!
（カメラマン）
幸田八段！ 桐山五段！
Excuse me, but do you mind if I get a few pictures?
すみません お写真の方
よろしいですか？
（零）どうしたらいい？
What should I do?
Should I tell him?
話すべきか
But if my adoptive father finds out, he'll...
でも このことを知ったら
父は…
そして 姉はどうなる？
And what'll happen to my adoptive sister?
Is there anything that I can do right now?
今 自分にできることは
ないんだろうか
What an incredible garden.
すごい庭だ
I can't believe a hotel in the city has a place like this.
都内のホテルの中に
こんな場所があるなんて
It's a pond.
池だ
Why do they always pass each other by?
（零）どうして
すれ違っていってしまうんだろう
Even though neither one of them wants to sever the relationship...
姉も父も お互いの存在を—
こんなにも
裁ち切り難く思ってるのに
A sun shower...
（零）天気雨…
（神宮寺）宗谷(そうや)！ おーい！
Souya!
Hey!
Hey, Souya!
おーい！ 宗谷！
There you are!
Hey, Souya! You numbskull!
おい こら 宗谷
このバカタレが！
Hey, man of the hour, I was wondering where you had...
おい こら 主役
もう 一体どこ消えたかと…
Look at you! You're soaked!
あ〜あ もう
ぬれてんじゃねえか
U-Um...
（零）あ あの…
Hey, Kiriyama!
おい 桐山！ お前
そばにいたなら連れてきてよ
If you were with him, you should've brought him in.
Come on, let's go. You too!
ほら 行くぞ！ お前も来い！
Okay. Sorry.
あっ はい すみません
Jeez, with the event starting,
this isn't where the main draw is supposed to be!
（神宮寺）もう…
会が始まるのに—
主役が ここにいて
いいわけなかろうよ もう
That took my breath away.
（零）息をのんだ
Because...
だって—
I didn't sense him there at all.
気配がなかった
The moment I laid eyes on him,
彼の姿を見た瞬間
世界から音が消えた
all the sound in the world disappeared.
His appearance hasn't changed at all.
（林田(はやしだ)高志(たかし)）姿が変わらないんだ
It's like time has stopped.
時間が止まってるっていうか
"He isn't human."
Somebody whispered in the depths of my memory.
（零）記憶の底で
誰かがささやいた
"He isn't human."
The moment he left,
彼が消えたその刹那—
the sky broke open and heavy rain began pouring down.
空が破け
重たい雨が降りだした
That's who he's going up against...
あの人と戦うのか
Silver Thread
Shimada...
島田さん…
The Water's Surface
It was a strange sight.
（零）不思議な光景だった
When he entered the hall,
彼が会場に入ると…
the room went silent,
（零）音が消え—
and the crowd parted for him.
人垣が二つに割れた
Sorry, everyone. Thank you for your patience.
ああ すいません 皆さん
お待たせしました
Turns out he was in the garden,
just gazing at the carp, all care-free!
こいつ庭にいましたよぉ
のんきに コイ眺めてました
Unbelievable, right?
もう やんなっちゃうよ ねえ
Well, shall we get started?
じゃ 始めましょっか
Come on, Souya, to the stage.
ほら 宗谷 壇上へ
He became a professional at 15, while still in junior high.
（零）15歳 中学生でプロになり—
At 21, he became the youngest Master in history.
21歳 最年少で名人に就位
その後 将棋界の歴史を
次々と覆し—
After that, he broke one record
after another in the shogi world,
and, for the first time in history, he won all seven major titles.
史上初 七大タイトル全てを制覇
Then ten-odd years passed.
そして それから十数年の年月
玉座に君臨し続けるも—
He continued to reign on the throne,
and his appearance remain unchanged.
その姿は変わることなく
Never fading, never tiring, never becoming corrupted.
褪(あ)せず 倦(う)まず 汚(けが)れず
With overwhelming strength,
圧倒的な力で そこに
he quietly continues to reside at the top.
静かに そこにあり続ける
（島田(しまだ) 開(かい)）ん？
Hey. It's been a while.
よお 久しぶり
He could be compared to a god,
（零）神に例えられるその一方で
誰かが言った
however, someone once said,
"I bet
きっと—
the devil has the same kind of face."
悪魔っていうのは
ああいう顔しているんだろうな
Then let's continue with Shimada, 8-dan, if you would.
（司会）では 続いて
島田八段 お願いします
Good evening, everyone.
（島田）皆様 こんばんは
I would like to thank all the fans for coming, despite it being a weeknight.
今日は 平日にもかかわらず—
多くのファンの方々に
お越しいただき—
ありがとうございます
It's been nearly three weeks since I became the challenger,
but the days have just flown by...
挑戦者になって
３週間ほどたちましたが—
非常に慌ただしい…
At the end of the night before the first match,
this is what Shimada said.
（零）前夜祭が終わるころ
島田さんが言った
I need two.
（島田）２つだ
I have to beat that monster twice and get two white stars.
あのバケモノを相手に
白星を まず２つ
Otherwise, I'll never get there.
でないと たどり着けない
20th Lion King Tournament Schedule
First match: March 3-4 - Ryuzanso Hotel (Tokyo)
Second match: March 10-11 - Matsunoki Lodge (Nagano Pref.)
Third match: March 19-20 - Zenkou Hotel (Tokushima Pref.)
Fourth match: March 25-26 - Kyoto Hotel Number Two (Kyoto)
Fifth match: April 2-3 - Kyushu Hakusen Hotel (Fukuoka Pref.)
Sixth match: April 9-10 - Tendou Ryuuryuu Hall (Yamagata Pref.)
Seventh match: April 17-18 - Hakone Hokubu Hotel (Kanagawa Pref.)
The sixth match...
六局目が俺のふるさとなんだ
Fourth match: March 25-26 - Kyoto 2nd Hotel (Kyoto)
Fifth match: April 2-3 - Kyushu Hakusen Hotel (Fukuoka Pref.)
Sixth match: April 9-10 - Tendou Ryuuryuu Hall (Yamagata Pref.)
Seventh match: April 17-18 - Hakone Hokubu Hotel (Kanagawa Pref.)
is in my hometown.
Shimada Kai, 8-dan.
（零）島田開 八段
獅子王戦 七番勝負
The Lion King Tournament is a seven-match showdown.
After 114 moves, he conceded the first match.
第一局 114手目にて投了
Rei.
（幸田香子）零
What do you want?
（零）用事って何？
You snitched on me to Dad, didn't you?
父さんに
余計なこと言ったでしょ？
My answer is the same as from my text.
メールで答えたとおりだよ
I didn't tell him anything.
僕は何も言ってない
He put a hold on my credit card,
and he's bombarding me with questions.
カード止められた上に—
いろいろ とにかく
質問攻めにされたわ
What am I supposed to do?
どうしたらいいのよ！
あんたのせいだからね
This is all your fault!
I told you, I didn't say anything!
だから 何も言ってないって
In fact, you brought it all on yourself!
…っていうか それ
姉さんの自業自得ってやつだろ？
（香子）はあ？ 自業自得？
I brought it on myself?
何？ それ
何？ その上から目線
What's that?
Are you looking down at me?
Who do you think you are?
あんた何様？
All you do is whine pitifully and play messy shogi!
ぐちぐち悩んで
グダグダの将棋指してるくせに！
That has nothing to do with this!
関係ないだろ！ この話とは
Shake
Shiver
あっ… モモちゃん？
Shake
Shiver
Momo?
Shake
Shiver
Rei, who are they?
零 誰よ？
あ あかりさん あっ… あの…
Akari, u-um...
（川本(かわもと)あかり）ん！
U-Um...
（零）あ あの…
Pardon us.
失礼しました
どうぞごゆっくり
Please, as you were.
A-A fight?
（川本モモ）
ケ… ケンカ 零ちゃん
Rei...
Come on, let's be on our way.
さ さっ 行きましょう
Will he get bullied?
いじめられてしまうの？
I think he'll be fine.
大丈夫よ 多分
It's too bad, but he was evidently in the middle of something.
（あかり）残念だけど…
ちょーっと
取り込み中だったみたいね
A witch? Is she a witch?
魔女… 魔女なの？
There's nothing we can do.
しかたないわね
Let's go home and eat the fried tofu pouches.
おいなりさんは
私たちで食べちゃいましょ
But...
（川本ひなた）でも…
はーっ… それにしても
零君も また手ごわそうな子を
Still, it seems Rei sure is dealing with a strong-willed girl.
Who are those people?
誰よ あの人たち
From the neighborhood...
（零）近所の…
世話になってる人たちだよ
They've done a lot for me.
（香子）ふ〜ん
今度は あの家なんだ
So that's the next home, huh?
You put on the "woe-is-me" act again and won them over?
また かわいそうぶって
取り込んだんでしょ？
また めちゃくちゃにするの？
Are you going in to another house and messing up another family?
人の家に上がり込んで…
You're a real piece of work.
いやらし
（ひなた）何だろう
What is it?
じれったくて 胸がバクバクした
I'm so irritated that my heart's beating like crazy.
Rei's expression was white like a stone.
石みたいに白い
零ちゃんの表情に
We've never seen him look like that before.
私たちの知らない横顔に
Not to mention,
そして 一度もこちらを…
he didn't even look...
向かないことに
in our direction!
Rei, eat these!
零ちゃん これ食べて！
Sis and I made them.
お姉ちゃんと作ったの
There's plenty of egg and sesame seeds in them, and they're sweet and really delicious!
タマゴとゴマが
いっぱい入ってて—
甘くて とてもおいしいから！
食べると元気出るから
絶対 食べて！
Eating them will cheer you up, so you better eat them!
Grrrr...
Junior High Student
Thank you.
ありがとう
Let's go, Sis!
（ひなた）行こう！ お姉ちゃん
What was with her?! I'm so pissed!
何あれ ムカつく！
絶対よくない あの女の人
That woman is definitely bad news!
Come on now, Hina. Hina.
これ ヒナ ヒーナ！
Don't say things like "pissed," okay?
ダメよ〜
ムカつくとか言っちゃ
Is the witch gone?
魔女 もういない？
And Rei too!
零ちゃんも零ちゃんだよ！
Why does he just take it and not say anything back?!
何 言われ放題で黙ってんのよ！
But...
（あかり）
でも… お姉ちゃんもそう思う
ちびっとね
I do agree with you.
A little.
Right?!
（ひなた）でしょー？
A little.
（あかり）ちびっとよ ちびっと…
Just a little.
The Water's Surface
Bottom of the Blue Night
何これ　あっまーっ
What is this? So sweet!
The fried wrapping is too sweet! It's not candy!
お揚げ甘すぎ
お菓子じゃないんだから
But this one has minced pickled wasabi in it.
でもこっちのは わさび漬けの
刻んだのが入ってるんだ
Ugh! When the flavors change, I can't stop eating them!
嫌だもう 味が違ったら
止まんないじゃない
キャッ！
太ったらどうしてくれんのよ
If I get fat, somebody'll be in trouble.
What am I supposed to do about that?
（零）そんなこと言われても…
You follow me home, eat my food, and then complain?
勝手について来て
勝手に食べて文句ですか
そうですか…
Is that how it is?
ふ〜ん
で 二の重には野菜系… 筑前煮？
And vegetables in the second layer...
Simmered chicken and vegetables? Old hags!
ババくさっ
アピール きっつ〜
Man, that's a hard sell.
Like, "See how domestic I am?"
“私 家庭的でしょ”みたいな？
Like, "This is just what a boy living on his own hankers for, isn't it?"
男の子の１人暮らし—
こーゆーのに
飢えてんでしょ的な
So there's okra and broccoli...
んで オクラとブロッコリ…
ふ〜ん？
Boiled with sesame oil and salt.
ゆでてゴマ油と塩… ナムル風か
Korean-style seasonings, huh?
Crunch
Munch
Lick
Sis, you'd better be getting home. Mom probably has dinner...
姉さん そろそろ帰らないと
母さんが晩ご飯…
I can't move.
動けない… スカートきつっ！
My skirt is too tight!
うっ うーん く… 苦しい
I-It hurts.
What?!
Now that I'm full, I feel sleepy.
おなかいっぱいになったら
何か眠くなってきちゃった
Rei, let me borrow your clothes. Do you have any sweatshirts?
ねえ 服貸して
ジャージとかないの？
I'm going to bed.
もう 寝る
Didn't Dad just get mad at you?
怒られたばっかでしょ 父さんに
Go home!
帰んなよ！
Shut up already. Jeez.
（香子）うっさいなー もう！
あとで電話すりゃ
いいんでしょ？
I'll just call them later, all right?
Don't go digging around and opening stuff!
ああ… 勝手に！
開けないでよ そこ
Toss
Swish
ああっ！ もう！
For crying out loud!
は〜っ やっと落ち着いた
I finally feel better.
Hey, which girl?
ねえ どの子よ？
はい？
What?
The one in junior high?
あの中坊？
Or don't tell me...
それとも まさか…
あの人妻じゃあないわよね
Not the housewife, right?!
Excuse me?
はい？
What are you talking about?
何の話さ
The housewife...
人妻って… ああ もしかして
あかりさんのこと？
Maybe you're referring to Akari?
So her name's Akari.
（香子）あかりっていうんだ…
I see.
へえ〜 どうでもいいけど
Not that I care.
She was carrying her little sister.
だっこしてたのは 妹だよ
What?
W-Witch?
Those three are sisters.
（零）あの３人は 姉妹だよ
These three
What?!
Incidentally, I don't think Akari is that much older than you.
（零）ついでに言えば
あかりさん—
姉さんと そんなに年
違わないと思うけど…
What?!
（香子）えーっ！ うそでしょー！
No way!
Then, which one?
じゃあ どっちよ
中坊と あのおば… 姉と
The junior high girl or the old wo... the oldest sister?
Which?
どっちって…
何でそうなるわけ？
Why would you think it'd be like that?
It's neither of them. And did you call her an "old wo..."?
どっちも違うよ
…っていうか
今 おば… って言った？
Don't tell me it's the kindergartner, then.
じゃあ まさか… あの園児？
You pervert!
この変態！
Look, just go home already!
（零）…っつか
帰ってよ もーっ！
I'm telling you,
（香子）だーかーらー
零の所だってば！
I'm at Rei's place!
You don't have a problem if I'm really at Rei's place, right?
本当に零の所なら
文句ないんでしょう？
That doesn't matter, seeing as the last train is long gone!
そんなこと言っても
もう電車ないんだってば！
零！
Rei.
（零）おーっと あっ あっ…
Jeez, what the hell?
（香子）ふん もう 何よ！
娘を 何で信用できないの？
Why can't he trust his own daughter?!
Grr
I don't understand Kyouko anymore!
Pout
Grr
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
Grr
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
I don't
under-
stand
Kyouko
anymore!
Yes, me neither.
ええ 僕もです
気が合いますね お父さん
We sure agree in that sense, Dad.
姉さん　どうするのさ これから
Sis, what are you going to do?
Dad's worried about you.
父さん 心配してたよ
I don't really care.
（香子）知らないわ
父さんて いつもズレてるのよ
Dad's always out of sync about something.
He said, "If you have a boyfriend who's taking care of you,
then bring him to the house so I can meet him."
お世話になってるなら
挨拶するから連れて来なさい—
彼氏を… だって！
The man's 20 years older than me, married,
20も年上で妻帯者で—
and on top of that, he's Dad's former disciple.
おまけに かつて
自分の弟弟子(でし)だった男よ
There's no way I can bring him home.
連れてけるわけないじゃない
Why did you choose a guy like that?
何で そんなやつ選んだんだよ
I don't know.
（香子）知らないわよ
I want to ask myself the same question.
私が聞きたいくらいよ
That little brat called me a witch.
あのチビ　人のこと
魔女とか言いやがって
If I really were a witch,
I wouldn't be dealing with these pathetic problems.
ほんとに魔女なら…
こんな情けない苦労してないわよ
Tell me, Rei. What should I do?
ねえ 零　どうしよう… 私
I'm...
怖い…
scared.
In the darkness of that night,
（零）その夜の間中
携帯の小さな液晶の明かりが—
the glow from her phone's small LCD screen
faintly lit her silhouette
幾度も…
over and over
幾度も
and over again.
彼女の輪郭を淡く染めるのを—
I watched it quietly.
ただ見ていた
The room was dyed blue,
as if we were at the bottom of the sea.
部屋中が青く染まって
深い水の底に二人で…
It felt like all we did was sink that night.
ただ ただ
沈んでいくような夜だった
When she said, "Well, see you around,"
“じゃあ またね”という言葉に—
“うん”と言いかけて
口をつぐんだ
I started to say, "Yeah," but then I clammed up.
Even though I felt torn that day when I left the house,
あの日 引き裂かれるような思いで
あの家を出たのに—
for my older sister...
姉も…
and for me, nothing has changed.
僕も…
こうして 何も変わらないまま
変えられないまま
And without being able to change,
we've been stuck somewhere between siblings and strangers, unable to become either.
きょうだいにも他人にも
なりきれないまま…
すみません 遅くなりました
I'm sorry for being late!
Oh, don't worry about it.
（島田）ああ いいよ いいよ
What? Did you run here?
何？ 走ってきたの？
I'm sorry. I was on cleaning duty, and it ran long...
（零）すみません
掃除当番が長引いて
"Cleaning duty."
掃除当番
ほほ〜 久々に聞くよ
I haven't heard those words in a while.
That phrase brings back memories.
懐かしいなあ その単語
I see.
そっか　お前
ほんとに まだ学生なんだなあ
You really are still a student.
Get inside already.
早く入ってくれ
Nikaidou has been waiting impatiently for your arrival.
さっきから二海堂が
お前のこと待ちかねててな
There you are, Kiriyama!
（二海堂）おおっ！ 来たか 桐山
I won the final match!
（二海堂）勝ったぞ！ 最終局
（重田(しげた)盛夫(もりお)）ああ…
So I'll be Class C1 next season, just like you!
これで 来期は
お前と同じＣ１だ！
声 でけえよ お前
あと 態度もな
Your voice is too loud.
And that attitude too. It annoys the hell out of me.
ほんとイラッとくるね
（二海堂）うふふ 重田さん
残留決定 おめでとうございます
Shigeta, congratulations on retaining your class.
My heart was really throbbing!
いや もう ドキドキでしたね
もうちょっとで—
I thought I was close to being in the same class as you!
同じクラスになれちゃうとこかと
思いましたよー！
What's that? What were you watching?
何それ？ どこ見てたの？
どこの将棋界の情報？
Which shogi world did you get that information from?
I was confident this season, so you got any complaints?
も 余裕のシーズンでしたが 何か？
（島田）う〜ん でもまあ
Well, it's good that no one got
any bad news this time around.
つらいニュースのやつが
いなくて何より
I managed to stay in Class A this season too.
俺も 今期 Ａ級残留確定したし
Although, how can I put it? I squeaked by.
まあ 何つーか
首の皮一枚っつーか
I was on the borderline and made it by a hair.
髪の毛一本の
ギリギリの線だったけどね
（重田）髪の毛一本… くっ…
Made it by a hair...
When Big Brother says that, it has weight.
（二海堂）兄者が言うと重みが…
I sincerely congratulate you!
本当に おめでとうございます
What's wrong?
（島田）どうしたの？
みんな目頭を押さえて
Why are you guys covering your face?
I finally caught up to you, Kiriyama.
ついに追いついたぞ 桐山
I'll be waiting for the day when we have a match together.
直接対決がかなうこと
楽しみにしてるぜ
Right, rival?
なあ ライバル
Yeah.
（零）ああ そうだな
When Nikaidou said that to me,
his face shone so bright that I had to squint,
（零）そう言った二海堂の表情が
まぶしすぎて目をすがめたら—
and the river from this morning floated across my eyelids.
まぶたに今朝の川面がよぎった
I'll turn eighteen next month.
来月 僕は18になり…
一年遅れで高２になる
And I'll begin my second year of high school, one year late.
Without being able to change anything,
何も変えられなかったまま—
once again...
また—
a new spring will come.
新しい春がやってくるのだ
Bottom of the Blue Night
Your fingers, your chest, your eyes
Are so dazzling there are nights when I get dizzy
They suddenly fall upon me, and it's just so warm
That it feels like I swallowed a seven-colored star
You held me tight, troubling me like a burning spark would
But I was taught to keep walking despite everything
God, please hear me out
For just a little while
Please connect us like that constellation
So that we're never away from each other
So that we're always together
Next Episode Preview
Episode 18
Hey, are you free tomorrow?
（島田）お前さあ
あした あいてない？
Then do you wanna go to Mouseland?
（林田）んじゃ 行くか？
ネズミーランド 男二人で！
Just us two guys!
Um, how can I put it?
（零）えーっと 何ていうか…
気持ち悪いっていうか…
It's disturbing, or like...
Illustration: Suetsugu Yuki
Please watch the next episode of "March comes in like a lion" too!
（二海堂）３月のライオン
次回もご覧ください
Kiriyama, my passionate battle
with you is just beginning!
桐山 お前との
熱い戦いはこれからだ
Here I come, my rival!
行くぞ！ ライバル